SSK字幕组 倾情译制
新浪微博｜@SSK字幕组　官网｜www.sskzmz.com
字幕仅供学习，请勿商用
转载请注明出处，版权归片方所有
翻译｜lala　洛狸　来入梦　Dark Paradise　REN
校对｜Luke　特效｜Bunny　压制｜hhjie　总监｜Luke
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
艾米·亚当斯
杰克·吉伦哈尔
夜行动物
迈克尔·珊侬
亚伦·泰勒-约翰逊
编剧 汤姆·福特
导演 汤姆·福特
亲爱的 顺便一提 你这样袒胸露乳
And by the way, honey, with all this decolletage
难道不应该对他
you should be getting a lot
产生更大的诱惑吗
more dickoletage than what he has to offer.
但是我想了一下
And as I can recall it,
是你告诉我 他高潮的时候
you were the one that told me that when he came,
精液和椰子汁一样稀
it was as thin as coconut water.
亲爱的 要是我的话肯定和他分了
Honey, that's a deal breaker for me.
的确很稀
It was that thin.
好吧 物以稀为贵嘛
Well, I see we're settling for less nowadays.
真是不可理喻
That's beyond.
莫罗太太 有你的包裹
Mrs. Morrow, a package arrived for you.
我今天早上在邮筒里看见的
I found it in the mailbox this morning.
我能问一下这个周末您属意谁值班吗
May I ask you who you'd like on duty this weekend?
呃 其实 不如这个周末大家都放假
Um, actually, why don't you give everybody the weekend off?
- 真的吗  - 嗯 真的
- Are you sure?  - Yeah, yeah.
我跟先生可能会去海滩别墅 呃
We might go to the beach house and, uh,
如果不去 独自享受周末也不错
if not, it might be nice to have a weekend alone.
- 我会通知其他人的  - 谢谢
- I'll let everyone know.  - Thank you.
喔 该死
Oh, damn it.
- 克里斯多夫  - 怎么了
- Christopher?  - Yes?
抱歉 你能帮我打开它吗 我刚被纸划伤了
I'm sorry. Can you help me open this? I just got a paper cut.
- 当然可以 这个放着我来  - 谢谢
- Yeah, of course. Here, let me do it.  - Thank you.
嗯嗯 我只是 被纸划了一个口子
Yeah, yeah. I just... A paper cut.
- 有一个便笺  - 你读一下
- There's a note.  - You can read it.
“亲爱的苏珊 ”
"Dear Susan, I've written
“我写了一部小说 将在春天出版”
a novel that will be published in the spring.
“这部小说和我们当初在一起时写的那些”
"It's different from the kind of things that I was writing
“不一样”
"When we were together."
你继续
Go ahead.
“分手的时候你给了我所需的创作灵感”
"In the end you left me with the inspiration that I needed
“用心创作”
"To write from the heart.
“我希望你是第一个读者”
"I wanted you to be the first to read it,
“所以我给你寄了一份样本”
so I'm sending along a proof.
“我会在洛杉矶出差到周三”
"I will be in la until Wednesday on business
“这么多年再次见到你肯定会很高兴”
"And it would be good to see you after so long.
“我的手机号码和邮箱地址都在下面 爱德华”
"My cell number and email address are below. Edward."
谢谢
Thanks.
早 早上好
Morning. Good morning.
那是什么 爱德华寄给我的手稿
What's that? It's a manuscript Edward sent me.
他写了一部小说
He wrote a novel.
哪个爱德华
Edward who?
前夫爱德华 你记得他的
Edward, my first husband. You remember him.
我不知道他还会写作
I didn't know he could write.
不 你知道 我们在一起的时候他就在写一部小说
Yes, you did. He was writing a novel when you and I got together.
你只是不想记得
You just don't remember.
你们二十年来有联系过吗
Have you guys even talked in 20 years?
十九年
19.
没有 我几年前
No. I tried calling him a
试过打给他 但是他挂了我的电话
couple of years back, but he hung up on me.
我还以为他在达拉斯的预科学校教英文
I think he's teaching English at some prep school in Dallas.
真的很替他难过 他没有再婚
It's sad, really. He never remarried.
你昨晚去哪了 为什么没来艺廊
Where were you last night? You didn't come by the gallery.
这的很抱歉 我
I'm sorry. Really, I...
我离开办公室的时候晚宴就已经迟到了
By the time I left the office, I was late for my dinner and...
只会占用你十五分钟
It would have taken you 15 minutes.
十五分钟而已 对我却是意义重大
Fifteen minutes, and it would have meant a lot to me.
算了
Never mind.
- 你昨晚没上床睡觉  - 我不想吵醒你
- You didn't come to bed last night.  - I didn't wanna wake you.
哦
Yeah.
其实 我昨晚没睡 我为艺展开幕而焦虑
Well, I wasn't asleep. I was too wound up from the opening.
顺便说一下 进展得很顺利 显而易见
It went well, by the way. Apparently.
很棒 是
Good. Yeah.
我们去海滩别墅怎么样
Look, why don't you and I go to the beach?
我们可以今晚去 星期一回来
We can go tonight and come back on Monday.
或许我们需要二人世界 独享这个周末
Maybe if we just spent some time, just the two of us?
你为什么星期六还穿这件西装
Why are you wearing this blazer on a Saturday?
因为我要回公司
Because I gotta go back to the office,
然后去机场
and then I gotta go to the airport,
再然后回纽约
and then I gotta go back to New York.
你刚从那里回来 是 我知道
You just came from there. Yes, I know.
但是如果我想做成这笔交易就必须再回去
But I have to go again if I wanna get this deal done,
我不想再去推销别的东西
and I don't wanna have to sell anything else.
- 该死  - 没关系
- Shit.  - It's okay.
你知道吗 这件事的吊诡之处在于
You know, the strange thing is is,
我不太在意这次艺展
I don't really care about all this art.
- 听起来不像你  - 我知道 但是真的
- That doesn't sound like you.  - I know, but it's true.
我在意
I care.
它让我很生气
It pisses me off.
我知道你很在意
I know you do.
别担心 我可以在墙上挂满洛杉矶新人们的作品
Don't worry, I can fill the walls with some new la artists
大家会以为
and people will think we're
我们走在时尚前沿 而不是濒临破产
ahead of the curve instead of going broke.
你不用为此感到为难
You won't have to be embarrassed.
事情有没有好一点
Are things a little better?
他现在事业上正步履维艰
He's just having a hard time with his business right now.
卡洛斯跟我说了
Carlos told me.
还真是惊讶 我还以为我们隐藏得很好
I'm surprised. I thought we were hiding it pretty well.
如果哈顿知道大家都心知肚明一定会很沮丧
Hutton would be very upset to find out anybody knew.
他只是不喜欢服输
He just hates not to win.
你现在能入睡吗
Are you sleeping?
你打电话给我的心理药理学家了吗 打了吗
Did you call my psychopharmacologist? Did you call him?
你应该打给他 因为他简直就是个天才
You should call him, because he's a genius.
我真的很担心你
I'm worried about you, seriously.
你看我一眼 看着我
Just look at me for a second. Look at me.
上次我们聊天的时候你吓到我了
You scared me the last time we talked.
我没事
I'm fine.
我很好 我
I am fine. I am...
我 我简直难以置信我对你和盘托出
I am. I just can't believe that I told you all of those things.
我只是有点窘迫 你懂的
I'm just kind of embarrassed, you know.
因为我有什么权利不高兴 我什么都有了
Because what right do I have to not be happy? I have everything.
不高兴我都觉得心中有愧
I feel ungrateful not to be happy.
你和所有人享有同等的权利 苏珊
As much right as anyone, Susan, as much right as anyone,
因为一切都是相对的
because it's all relative.
你只是对自己太严苛了
You're just awfully hard on yourself.
你过得怎么样
How do you do it?
你是说跟卡洛斯在一起 我只是 我对此完全无感
You mean with Carlos? I just... it's... I'm totally cool with it.
而且有一个同志丈夫也不是一件特别糟糕的事 你懂吗
And having a gay husband is not such a bad thing, you know?
我们是闺蜜 我们彼此深爱着对方
We're best friends. We love each other completely.
我绝对是他生活里唯一的女人
I'm certainly the only woman in his life.
而且这比肉欲更长久 不是吗
And that lasts longer than lust, doesn't it?
简直就是永恒
It's forever, really.
我和哈顿之间没有这种感觉
Hutton and I don't have that.
你有过吗
Did you ever?
我觉得我们只是想要不同的东西
I think we just want different things,
或者是我想要的不一样
or I want different things.
你还爱他吗
Do you still love him?
他在叫我 失陪一下
I'm being summoned. Pardon me.
他要赶飞机 我要跟他道别
He has to catch a plane. I'm gonna say goodbye.
希望这笔交易能成功
I hope this deal works out for you.
我真的希望 我知道你需要它 是我们需要它
I really do. I know you need it. We need this.
不 是你需要
No. You need this.
- 拜  - 拜
- Bye.  - Bye.
所以我说
So I said,
“嗯 我妈经常跟我说”
"Well, my mother always told me
“如果你在婴儿出生前一个月”
"If you massage your pussy with Pam cooking spray
“用喷雾油按摩阴道”
"A month before the baby comes,
“你都不需要进行阴道修复手术”
"You don't need vaginal rejuvenation."
我要去买一些喷雾
I've gotta get some Pam.
她今年要被提名了
And she is going to get a nomination this year.
只是提名吗 她志在必得
A nomination? She's gonna win.
我们聊聊你的艺术展开幕吧
Let's talk about your opening.
- 我的最爱  - 不是我最爱的
- My favorite subject.  - Not mine.
昨晚的开场真是引人入胜
The opening was spectacular last night.
真的吗 这就是你以为的
Really? That's what you thought?
- 什么 你不是这样想的吗  - 不是
- What, you didn't?  - No.
我觉着这部作品真是难以置信的强大
I thought the work was incredibly strong.
在我们生活的垃圾文化中简直熠熠生辉
So perfect with all this junk culture that we live in.
垃圾 那是垃圾
It's junk. It is junk.
完全就是垃圾
Total junk.
亲爱的 你真的很成功
Darling, you are a big success.
- 没有人真正喜欢自己的工作  - 那为什么我们还要做
- No one really likes what they do.  - Then why do we do it?
因为我们是迫不得已
Because we're driven.
也许还缺乏安全感
Maybe a bit insecure.
年轻的时候我们沉迷其中
We get into things when we're young
因为我们以为它们意义重大
and because we think they mean something.
之后我们发现原来它们索然无味
And then we find out that they don't.
哦 苏珊 享受这荒谬的世界吧
Oh, Susan, enjoy the absurdity of our world.
这样才不会那么痛苦
It's a lot less painful.
相信我 我们的世界
And believe me, our world
要比尘世少很多痛苦
is a lot less painful than the real world.
为什么我们要开这个老古董去玛法[美国德州的一座城市]
Yeah, why are we driving this old thing to marfa?
因为我刚把它重新拾掇了一番 这可是一代经典
Because I just had it completely rebuilt. It's a classic.
它的音响系统真的很烂
It has a terrible sound system.
好吧 你还是要忍受它
Well, you're gonna have to suffer through that.
你居然有两双长筒靴吗 尹迪亚
You have two sets of boots, India?
我们今晚真的要停下来吗 我宁愿直接到那儿
Do we really have to stop tonight? I'd rather just get there.
好了 问你妈吧 她说了算
All right, ask your mother. She's the boss.
我定了闹钟
I set the alarm.
尹迪亚 你已经玩了四个小时了
India, you've been on that thing for hours.
我以为你想开夜车的
I thought you were the one who wanted to drive all night.
是 但是我们能做什么呢
I did, but what are we supposed to do,
唱篝火之歌还是什么
sing campfire songs or something?
- 还要多久  - 不知道
- How much longer?  - I don't know.
三小时 或者三个半小时
Like three, three and a half hours.
嗯 爸 这下你心满意足了
Well, dad, you're gonna get your wish.
我的手机没信号了
My cell service just went out.
天呐 你能相信这里竟然没信号吗
Jesus, can you believe there's no service here?
这怎么可能
How is that even possible?
我最喜欢西德克萨斯两件事
Two of the things I love most about west Texas,
没有信号 人烟稀少
no phones and no people.
哦 拜托
Oh, come on.
真是混蛋 甩掉他们了吗
Total jerks. Are we rid of them?
- 尹迪亚 不要这样  - 什么
- India, don't do that.  - What?
- 什么 她做了什么  - 她对他们竖中指
- What? What'd she do?  - She just gave 'em the finger.
- 妈妈 妈妈 我好怕  - 托尼
- Mom. Mom, I'm scared.  - Tony.
加速
Speed up.
- 没事 没事  - 不 我不喜欢这样
- It's all right, it's all right.  - No, I don't like this.
没事
It's all right.
加速 托尼
Speed up. Tony.
该死 哦 太好了
Shit. Oh, good.
就让他们走 让他们走
Just let 'em go. Let 'em go.
尹迪亚 不要看他们
India, don't look at them.
- 但是他们在看我  - 不要给他们任何借口
- But, they're...  - Just don't give them any reason.
他为什么笑成那样
Why is he smiling like that?
我不知道 亲爱的 没事的
I don't know, sweetheart. It's all right. It's all right.
喔
Whoo!
他疯了吧
He's crazy.
- 哦 天呐  - 哦 天呐
- Oh, my god.  - Oh, my god.
该死
Shit.
嘿 混蛋 靠边停车 快他妈停车
Hey, motherfucker, pull over. Pull the fuck over!
哦 天呐 托尼
Oh, god, Tony.
尹迪亚 你的手机现在能用吗 尹迪亚
India. Is your phone working yet, India?
不能 但我把车牌号记下来了
No, no, but I took down the license number.
不
No.
哦 不
Oh, no.
- 靠边停车 快他妈停车  - 爸爸 爸爸
- Pull over. Pull the fuck over!  - Dad. Dad.
嘿 混蛋 靠边停 靠边停
Hey, asshole, pull over. Pull over.
哦 不 你想从我们这里得到什么
Oh, no. What do you want from us?
别怕 别怕
Easy, easy. Easy, easy!
够了
Stop it!
该死
Shit.
嘿 拜托
Hey, come on!
别担心 亲爱的 没事的
Don't worry, honey. It's okay.
他们可能有枪
They probably have a gun.
求求你了 托尼 开出去
Please, Tony, pull out.
动不了 他把车堵住了
I can't move. He's blocked the car.
他在干嘛
What's he doing?
没事的 不要下车
It's okay. Don't get out the car.
我不会下车的 亲爱的
I'm not getting out of the car, sweetheart.
- 晚上好  - 晚上好
- Good evening.  - Good evening.
你知道有事故应该停车的 对不对
You know you're supposed to stop when there's an accident, right?
是 我知道 那你为什么不停
Yeah, I know that. Why didn't you stop, then?
没用的
That won't work.
这里没信号
No signal here.
你不应该
You're not supposed to
肇事逃逸 这是犯罪
leave the scene of an accident. It's a crime.
- 你那么开车谁能不撞  - 对不起 你说什么
- After the way you were driving...  - I'm sorry, what'd you say?
你开车的方式简直离奇
Just the way you were driving was crazy.
嘿 特克
Hey, turk.
- 不要再靠近了  - 没事 亲爱的 没事的
- Don't come any closer.  - All right, sweetheart. It's all right.
请你们
You know, please just get
回到车里 别管我们
back in your car now and leave us alone.
不要慌 我们要举报一起事故 就这样
Calm down. We got an accident to report, that's all.
- 镇静 嘿 小姐  - 这只是一个手电筒 亲爱的
- Calm down. Hey, lady, lady, lady.  - It's a flashlight, sweetheart.
只是一个手电筒 没事
It's just a flashlight. It's all right.
- 天呐  - 好 我们交换一下信息
- Jesus Christ.  - Okay, so let's exchange information.
信息 对
Information? Yeah.
交换信息 把它从储物箱里拿出来
Let's exchange information. Get it out of the glove compartment.
好啊 我是双子座 我最喜欢的颜色是浅桃红
Okay, I'm a gemini. My favorite color's pale pink.
我喜欢远途散步和小猫
I like long walks and kittens.
我们应该 你知道吗 我们应该叫警察
We should... you know what? We should call the police.
- 哦 哦 真的吗  - 是
- Oh, oh? Really?  - Yeah. Yeah.
想法很好
That's a great idea.
- 这他妈全是你的错 对不对  - 什么
- It was your fucking fault, right?  - What?
是谁的错不重要 让我们走吧
It doesn't matter whose fault it was. Let's get going.
嘿 瑞 这些人车胎爆了
Hey, ray, these guys have got a flat tire.
当然了 嗯 你知道吗
They sure do. Well, what do you know?
- 他说什么  - 别信他 爸爸
- What'd he say?  - Don't believe it, dad.
- 他说我们车胎爆了  - 他说了什么
- He said we had a flat tire.  - What did he say?
别信他 我们车胎没爆
Don't believe him. We don't have a flat.
什么 什么
What? What?
没错 你的左胎爆了 确实是
Yep, your left tire's flat. It sure is.
一定是你在路上挤我们的时候爆的
Must have bust it when you were shoving us off the road.
我们没挤你 是你挤我们
We did not shove you off the road. You shoved us off the road.
- 你睁眼说瞎话  - 你认为我在骗你
- It's a lie.  - You think I'm a liar?
没事 没事
It's okay. It's okay.
- 她还是个孩子  - 你觉得我是骗子
- She's just a child.  - You think I'm a liar?
不是 她没那么说 兄弟 她还是个孩子
No, she's not saying that, man. She's just a child.
你车胎没爆 继续开啊
You don't got a flat, go on, drive.
- 开引擎 继续开  - 快开
- Start the engine and drive. Please drive.  - Just drive.
开车啊 混蛋 没人拦着你 开走啊
Just drive on it, asshole. Nobody's stopping you. Drive away.
走 滚开
Go. Fuck off.
臭傻逼
Stupid motherfucker.
- 该死  - 哦 天呐 哦 天呐
- Shit. God damn it!  - Oh, god. Oh, god.
- 哦 天呐  - 没关系 没事的
- Oh, god.  - It's okay. It's all right.
有事 我们前不着村后不着店
It's not okay. We're in the middle of nowhere.
我们该怎么办 托尼 我们怎么办
What are we gonna do, Tony? What are we gonna do?
我们要怎么办 托尼
What are we gonna do, Tony?
这样吧
I tell you what.
我们会帮你修好的 是不是 兄弟们
We'll fix it for you, won't we, guys?
是 当然了
Yeah, sure.
真的吗 真的
Really? Yeah.
让你看看我们是好人 我们会帮你修好
Just to show you we're okay, we'll fix it for you.
你什么都不用干
You won't have to do a thing.
然后我们会一起去找警察 对吧
Then we'll go to the cops together, right?
你和我 举报你的行驶事故 好吗
You and me, report your accident. All right.
谢谢 听起来很好吧
Thank you. Sound good?
- 嗯  - 谢谢
- Yeah.  - Thank you.
- 你有工具吗 先生  - 呃 其实 我
- You got tools, mister?  - Um, I actually, I...
不需要 用我们的 来吧 开始吧
No need. Use ours. Come on, let's get going.
不用 没事 没事
No, it's fine, it's just fine.
我不会修轮胎 所以 我不能 我需要他们的帮助
I can't fix a tire, so I can't... I need their help.
不要和他们有眼神接触
Please don't make eye contact with them.
你有备胎吗 兄弟
You got a spare tire, man?
没有备胎不能换轮胎
Can't change a tire without a spare.
你能给我后备箱的钥匙吗
You wanna give me the keys to the trunk?
- 不 不要  - 你他妈以为你是谁
- No, don't.  - Who the fuck do you think you are?
打开后备箱吧 亲爱的
Just pop the trunk, honey.
我来拿
I got it.
不要紧 我拿到了 太好了
That's all right, I got that. That's fine.
就在下面 给你
It's right underneath here. There you go.
就在下面
Just right under there.
里面好多东西
Just got a lot of things in here.
就在那下面
It's just right under there.
对不起 让女人下车
Sorry. Get the women out of the car.
快点 让她们下车
Come on, get 'em out.
快点 兄弟
Come on, man.
要用千斤顶把你的汽车升起来 所以让他们出来
Gotta lift your car up on the Jack, so get 'em out.
兄弟 他能顶得起来你的老婆孩子和车吗
Dude. Has he gotta lift your wife and your child and the car?
- 是 是  - 让你的老婆孩子下车
- Right, right.  - Get your women out the car.
没事的 亲爱的
It's all right, honey.
下车吧 她们需要修车
Just get out of the car. They need to fix the car.
他们是好人 他们只是要修轮胎
They're fine. They're just fixing the tire.
到这边来
Come over here.
快点 这边 你看到你对我的车做了什么吗
Come on, here. Have you seen what you did to my car?
你他妈的还以为自己多了不起
You think you're fucking hot shit,
- 是不是  - 你在说什么
- don't you?  - What are you talking about?
他们肯定觉得自己他妈的特别了不起
They definitely think they're fucking hot shit.
- 谁  - 你认真的吗
- Who?  - Are you serious?
- 你那两个臭婊子啊 不然还有谁  - 听着
- Your bitches, man. Who else?  - Look...
你觉得自己不得了是吧
No, you think you're so special,
可以随便撞别人的车
you can just bump another guy's car...
我没有这个意思 我只是想
No, we were just trying to get...
是你在危险驾驶
you were playing some kind of crazy game.
喂
Hey!
- 天哪  - 天哪
- Oh, my god.  - Oh, god.
天哪
Oh, my...
你们的警察叔叔走了哦
There goes your cops.
下次记得大点声
You should have tried harder to stop 'em.
没关系 就让我们来好好照顾你们吧
That's okay. It's okay. We'll take good care of you.
自以为是的臭婊子
Fucking bitch. Uppity rich bitch.
今天我就要好好教训你们
I'll teach you a fucking thing or two.
没事的
It's okay.
干啥 你瞅啥
What? What you looking at?
- 牛逼哄哄的  - 什么意思
- Hotshot.  - What do you mean?
你在路上想干嘛
What are you trying to do there on the road, huh?
你在说什么 你什么意思
What? I... What are you talking about?
听着
Look, look, look...
我们当时只是
We... we are... we are just
正常开车而已
trying to get where... Where we are going.
要开去哪
Where's that?
- 我问你们要开去哪  - 去玛法
- I said where you going?  - To marfa.
去玛法干什么
What exactly is in marfa?
- 聋了是吧  - 喂
- Hey, motherfucker...  - Hey!
- 别碰我爸爸 混蛋  - 兄弟 别动手
- Leave my dad alone, asshole!  - Leave me alone, man.
活得不耐烦了吧
Fuck you, baby.
她没有恶意 小孩子乱说话而已
She didn't mean that. She's just a kid.
你爸爸有什么不肯告诉我的 你愿意说吗
Your daddy won't tell me, so why don't you?
放开我 你管这么多干什么
Let me go! What's it to you anyway?
- 听着 我们不是坏人  - 别碰我女儿
- Look, we're nice guys.  - Don't touch my daughter!
我们只是在路上开车而已
We're just trying to get to where we're going.
要跳个舞吗
You wanna dance? Wanna dance?
就这样吗 不肯说吗
Oh, is that it? That all?
看看你爸爸
Baby, look at your daddy.
他觉得他比我好得多是吧
He thinks he's so much better than me, huh?
你觉得呢 他比我好得多吗
What do you think? What do you think?
- 没错  - 你好好看着他
- Well, he is.  - I mean, seriously, look at him.
放开她
Let her go!
你这个人渣
You're scum, you know!
不 放开我
No! No! Hey! Hey, get off.
混蛋 你给我小心一点
Hey, watch it, you fucking assholes.
你没资格这样跟我说话
You got no fucking right talking to me like that.
妈的 修你的轮胎去
Christ's sake! Fixing your goddamn tire.
走吧走吧
Let's go and get the fuck out of here, y'all.
尹迪亚
India.
别哭了宝贝 没事的
Don't cry, sweetie. It's fine.
你们没事吧 要纸吗
You all right over there? Need a tissue?
天哪 看上去不妙 你要不要纸
God damn, that looks bad. You might need...
- 我没事  - 宝贝 你有卫生棉条吗
- I’m fine.  - Hey, honey, you got a tampon?
- 你的鼻子看上去糟透了  - 我没事
- Your nose looks like shit.  - All right, I'm fine.
- 我说你的鼻子看上去糟透了  - 我没事
- I mean it looks like shit.  - I’m fine.
真可惜 我们好了没
This is bad news. We good?
我们好了
We're good. We're set.
- 我们可以走了  - 走吧
- We're good to go.  - Let's go.
好了 完事了
All right. We're good.
好了
All right. Yeah.
这条路还要开多久才有信号
How far up the road till we can get a signal?
你为什么还要继续开
Why do you wanna get further up the road?
又想逃离事故现场吗
So you can leave the scene of an accident again?
离他远点
Leave him alone.
- 贝利镇那边就有信号了  - 好吧
- There's service up by Bailey.  - All right.
但是你觉得我们要怎么去那里呢
How do you think we're gonna get there, though?
- 开车  - 开哪辆车
- In our cars.  - Which car?
两辆都开啊
In both cars.
- 先生 别想跟我耍把戏  - 什么
- Mister, don't try no fucking shit with me.  - What?
我知道你想搞什么名堂
You heard me. I know what you're doing. I know what your plan is.
- 怎么了  - 别想跟我耍把戏
- What is the matter?  - Don't try no fucking shit with me.
到底怎么了 你是不是有病
No, what is the matter, man? What the fuck is wrong with you?
我怎么知道你会不会
How do I know you ain't just
一脚油门就跑了 把我们扔在这里
gonna floor the gas and leave me in the dust?
你们开你们的车
You get in your car and
我们开我们的车 跟在你们后面
we'll get in ours and we'll follow you there.
- 去死吧 想得美 你去开我那辆  - 什么
- Fuck you! No way. You go in my car.  - What?
你跟我们来 让卢来开你那辆车
You come with us. Lou can drive your car.
不 我坚决不同意
No, I'm not gonna do that. No.
那好吧 你开你的车 让那个女孩来我们车上
Okay, fine, you drive your car and the girl comes with us.
- 什么 不行  - 宝贝儿 过来
- What? No!  - You come with us, baby.
听好了宝贝 我可不想玩什么老鹰捉小鸡
Listen, honey, I ain't after your fucking ass.
别碰我
No, don't touch me.
别这样
You are not doing that.
- 宝贝儿 你就喜欢这样不是吗  - 放开我
- Yeah, baby. You like it like that, huh?  - Let me go!
不 等等
No. Hey, wait!
你想干什么
What are you doing?
住手 放开她 求你们了
Stop! Get off her, please!
到那边去
Go over there.
放开她
Get your hands off her!
尹迪亚
India.
拜拜甜心 我爱你
Bye-bye, sweetheart. I love you.
尹迪亚
India...
- 求你们了 放我走吧  - 别碰她
- Let go of me, please.  - Get your hands off her.
妈的
Shit.
尹迪亚
India...
看看你们干的好事
Look what you gone and did.
没事了 没事了
Hey, hey. It's okay.
她是一家之主吗
She the boss? Is she the boss of your family?
- 劳拉  - 你有阴道吗
- Laura?  - Have you got a vagina?
我问你有没有阴道
Have you got a fucking vagina there?
喂
Hey!
- 劳拉  - 阴道哥
- Laura!  - Vagina boy!
- 把她弄进车里  - 阴道哥
- Just get her in the car. Get her in the car.  - Vagina boy!
- 滚  - 你想惹事儿是不
- Stay away!  - You want fucking something, boy?
- 托尼  - 你是不是惹事
- Tony.  - You want something?
- 托尼  - 劳拉
- Tony.  - Laura.
- 快进车里  - 好了快走
- Get in the car.  - Okay, here we go.
我们两辆车都开走 喂 卢
We're goin' in both cars. Hey, Lou.
不
No.
爸爸
Dad. Dad.
- 喂  - 爸爸
- Hey!  - Dad. Dad.
喂 停车
Hey! Wait! No.
不 别这样 求你们了
No! Please, no! No! No! Please...
苏珊
Susan?
你为什么不打电话告诉我你安全到达了
Why didn't you call me and let me know you got in safely?
因为现在才凌晨四点 我不想吵醒你
'Cause it's 4:00 in the morning. I didn't wanna wake you.
如果你失眠的话 为什么不吃药呢
If you can't sleep, why don't you take one of your pills?
你在哪
Where are you?
我刚进宾馆大门
I'm just walking in the door of the hotel.
- 先生 请问您要去哪一层  - 三十一层 谢谢
- What floor, sir?  - 31, please.
我们平时不住那层
That's not our usual floor.
我们平时那间房间有人住了
No, our regular room wasn't available.
你真应该看看我在大堂发火的样子
You should have seen the scene I caused in the lobby.
你在飞机上睡得好吗
I hope you got some sleep on the plane.
我很担心你 虽然你可能没意识到
I do worry about you. Even though you think that I don't, I do.
你肯定很累了
You must be exhausted.
- 我讨厌那个航班 真的  - 三十一层到了 女士
- I hate that flight. It's really not...  - 31, madam.
我到了 我先挂了 一会打给你 苏珊
I'm at my floor. I gotta run. I'll call you later, okay? Susan?
苏珊 听得见吗
Susan, can you hear me?
听得见
Yes. Yes, I heard you.
好好睡一觉
Get some sleep.
你来开
You're driving.
- 是这个路口吗  - 什么路口
- Is this the exit?  - Exit for what?
- 去贝利镇的路口  - 继续开
- Well, for Bailey.  - Keep going.
继续开 开快点
Keep going. Speed up.
- 你们到底要对我们做什么  - 就是这里 沿这条路开下去
- What the fuck are you doing to us?  - Here. Turn down here.
去死吧 我不会沿这条路开的
No, fuck you. I am not going down that road.
先生 还想见到你的妻子和女儿吗
Listen, mister, you wanna see your wife and kid?
那就沿这条路开下去
Then turn down the road.
你现在要哭了吗
You gonna cry now?
我们刚刚路过的那辆车是我的
That's my car we just passed.
不是你的 继续开
It ain't your car, man. Keep going.
你没必要担心你的妻子和女儿
I don't think you need to worry about your wife and kid.
我说过了 没必要担心她们
Like I say, you don't need to worry about them.
你什么意思
What do you mean, I don't need
什么叫我不需要担心她们
to worry about them? What the fuck does that mean?
冷静点 他可从来没杀过人
Calm down. He ain't never killed nobody yet, that's all I mean.
至少我认识他的时候不会
Least as far as I know he ain't.
杀人 你什么意思
Killed? What are you talking about, killing?
我说他没杀过人
I said he ain't killed nobody yet.
看来你没认真听我说话
If you'd listen to me, you'd hear what I was saying.
好吧 看上去已经开到头了 但是还没有见到她们
Well, looks like we've run out of road and they ain't here.
可能我指错路了吧
I wonder if I made a mistake.
现在你可以下车了 好吗
It's time for you to get out now, okay?
- 下车  - 你想做什么
- Get out!  - What are you... What are you doing?
- 小心点 不然弄死你  - 等等
- You'll get killed if you don't watch it.  - Wait.
停车
Wait!
不 停车
No, wait. Wait, wait, wait!
不
No! No!
你把他扔在那荒郊野外的做什么
What did you fucking leave him out here for?
喂 先生
Hey, mister!
你妻子找你
Your wife wants you!
上车去
Get in the fucking car.
先生 你妻子找
Hey, mister! Your wife!
先生
Mister!
妈的
Shit.
喂
Hey.
Hey!
喂
Hey! Hey!
Hey.
我可以借个电话吗
May I use your phone?
哈斯廷斯先生 这附近
Mr. Hastings, there's no town
没有叫贝利的镇啊
near here called Bailey.
我最害怕的事情发生了
I was afraid of that.
街对面有家旅馆 你身上有钱吗
There's a motel across the street. You got money?
我有信用卡
I have... I have credit cards.
天还很早呢 哈斯廷斯先生
It's still early, Mr. Hastings.
有线索我们会联系你
But we'll call if we get anything.
非常感谢
All right, thank you.
喂
Hello?
我是格里弗斯警长
This is lieutenant graves.
他们在一处干涸的河床里找到了你的车
They found your car over in a dried-out arroyo at topping.
- 那我的妻子和女儿呢  - 仍然没有消息
- What about my wife and daughter?  - Still no news.
她们不在车里
They weren't in the car.
我们把这个案子移交给安德斯警长了
We're turning the case over to lieutenant andes.
他想问你几分钟后能不能去接你
He wants to know if he can pick you up in a few minutes.
我已经准备好了
Yeah, I'm ready now.
早上好 很高兴见到你
Morning. Oh, glad to meet you.
我是波比·安德斯 负责这一带的警长
I'm Bobby andes. I look into things around here.
- 是你找到的我的车吗  - 他们在河床上找到的
- You found my car?  - They found it in a creek bed.
我们打算把你带到你报警的那户人家去
Tell you what, we take you back to the house we picked you up at,
你能从那里找回事发地点吗
you think you could backtrack from there?
我试试看
I could try.
好的 尽力吧 走吧
Okay, then, you try. Let's go.
根据我的理解 这些家伙没有枪是吗
It's my understanding these fellas didn't have any guns.
没有
No.
好的
All right.
那我就直接问了 你说有一个名叫卢的家伙
So let me get this straight, you say some fella named Lou
开车把你带到树丛里并且把你丢在那了是吗
just drove you out into the brush and left you there?
- 不 是他强迫我开车  - 他强迫你开车
- No, he made me drive.  - He made you drive.
然后你想往外走的时候
And then when you started to walk out,
又看见他们回来了
you saw 'em coming in again.
- 是的  - 他们开的谁的车
- Yes.  - Hmm. Whose car were they in?
我觉得应该是我的车
I think it was mine.
你觉得 你为什么会这么觉得呢
You think? What makes you think that?
看上去和听上去都像是我的 听上去像
By the look of it and the sound of it. It sounded like my car.
你在黑暗中看得清他们吗
Could you see 'em in the dark?
- 看不清  - 他们说了什么吗
- Not very well.  - Did they say anything?
他们说 先生 你妻子找你
They said, "Mister, your wife wants you."
你并没有走过去 为什么呢
You didn't go to 'em. Why didn't you go to 'em?
我不知道为什么 当时我
I don't know why I didn't go. I was...
好了
Okay.
从这里开始你能指路吗
Can you take it from here?
可以 我从高速公路上下来的 走了很久
Yeah, I came down the highway and I walked for a long time,
因为根本没有人为我停车
'cause no one stopped for me.
警官 沿路肩慢慢倒回去
Sergeant, back up slowly down the shoulder.
打开信号灯
Put your signal lights on.
停车 停车
Stop the car. Stop the car!
我就是从那处铁丝网钻出来的
I came out of that barbwire fence right there.
就在那个反射器边上 我记得很清楚
Right by the reflector. I remember that.
下车吧 接下来步行 你说你是走出来的对吧
Let's get out and walk. You said you walked out, right?
我就从这里出来的
I came up... I came up right here,
因为我一直沿着那个沟壑走的
'cause I walked along that arroyo over there.
这里以前是个田野
This is part of the old valdes place.
那边过去一点是以前的牧牛场
There's an old cattle station down that way a bit
旁边是烧垃圾的地方
next to where they burn their garbage.
这条路通向那里
This road leads to it.
她还好吧
Is she all right?
妈妈 是你吗 没事吧
Mom? Is that you? Is everything all right?
没事 我只是想听听你的声音
Yeah, yeah, it's fine. I just wanted to hear your voice.
我想你了
I miss you.
你把我吵醒了 我还在睡觉 今天礼拜天啊妈妈
You woke me up. I'm still in bed. It's Sunday morning, mom.
我能之后再打给你吗
Can I call you later?
可以 没事 继续睡吧宝贝
Yeah. Yeah, call me later. Go back to bed, sweetheart.
你听起来怪怪的 没事吧
You sound weird. Are you okay?
没事
I'm fine. I'm fine.
继续睡吧
Go back to bed.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
Me too.
- 我等会打给你  - 好的
- I’ll call you later.  - Okay.
爱德华 是你吗
Edward? Edward?
嗨 苏珊
Hi. Susan.
嗨 天哪 你好
Hi. God. How are you?
- 见到熟面孔真是太好了  - 见到你真高兴
- It's good to see someone I know.  - It's good to see you.
你还是那么美
You look beautiful, as always.
你在纽约干什么呢
What are you doing in New York City?
我来这里参加哥大奖学金的面试
I'm here for an interview for a scholarship at Columbia.
哥大 我以为你在德克萨斯州立大学呢
Columbia? I thought that you were at the university of Texas
你不是要当作家吗
becoming a great writer.
作家 没有吧
A great writer? I mean, I don't... I don't think so.
好吧 没错
Well, I am...
你不是在耶鲁要当艺术家吗
But aren't you at Yale becoming a great artist?
我已经从耶鲁毕业了 现在在哥大读硕士
Graduated Yale, but I'm at Columbia getting my master's degree.
- 哇  - 艺术史专业
- Oh, wow.  - Yeah, art history.
太棒了
That's great. Yeah.
你在纽约还认识别人吗
Listen, do you know anybody else in New York?
- 除了你没了  - 好吧
- Just you.  - Just me.
那要一起吃个晚饭吗
Okay, well, would you like to go to dinner?
- 好啊  - 好
- Absolutely.  - Okay.
先等我
Okay, great. Just let me...
先等我回公寓把这些东西放下吧
Just let me drop off my packages at my apartment.
要我帮你拿着吗 我可以帮你拿
All right, do you want me to grab them for you? I can hold that.
好啊 谢谢 我真怀念德州的男人
Yeah, great. Thank you. Oh... I miss Texas men.
德州可没有这样的暴雪
You don't have blizzards like this in Texas.
对啊
No, you don't.
你知道我们在哈斯廷斯的时候你是我第一个暗恋对象吗
You know that you were my first crush when we were at Hastings?
我当时和你哥哥关系那么好
I only spent so much time
只是为了有机会多靠近你一点
around your brother just to be around you.
他第一个暗恋对象可是你
Well, you were his first crush.
- 什么  - 真的
- What?  - Yeah.
我可一直都不知道库珀是同性恋啊
Well, I had no idea Cooper was gay.
我觉得那时候他自己都不知道 但是他真的很喜欢你
I don't think he knew back then, but he was obsessed with you.
唔
Mmm.
- 哇  - 真的
- Wow.  - Yeah.
如果我当时没发现你总是盯着我的话
If I hadn't caught you staring at me so much,
我还以为你跟他搞在一起了呢
I would have thought you were sleeping with him.
我 说实话 挺内疚的
I, actually... I feel terrible.
好多年没有跟他联系了
I haven't called him in a few years.
我一定是个很不称职的朋友 我希望没有伤害到他
I feel like I've been a bad friend. I hope I didn't hurt him.
你挺好的
You're good, you know that?
真的 大多数男人如果听说
No, you are. Most guys would have freaked out
自己最好的哥们爱上了自己 估计早就吓跑了
if they found out their best friend was in love with them.
你人很好
You're very sweet.
你可以打电话给他 他会很高兴的
You should call him. He would like that.
我们的父母差不多已经和他断绝关系了
My parents have basically disowned him.
他们几乎没有联系了
They're not really talking anymore.
- 为什么  - 你不知道为什么吗
- Why?  - Why? Are you serious?
你知道我父母就是那样的人
Well, you know my parents, right?
虔诚的教徒 保守派 性别歧视 种族歧视
They're religious, conservative, sexist, racist,
共和党 唯物主义者 纳粹主义者 种族歧视
republican, materialistic, narcissistic, racist.
还有很多很多
I could keep going...
我只是想知道你是怎么想的 苏珊
I'm just wondering what you really think, Susan.
我知道库珀是认真的
It's true, I know.
但是他们总是把我们看成他们的影子
But they just see us as a reflection of themselves,
所以他们不能接受库珀不是他们想要的样子
so they can't accept Cooper for who he is.
我也不知道自己要怎么做
I'm not sure how I'm gonna fare.
你和他们关系也不好吗
Aren't you being a little hard on them?
不好
No.
他们对我的生活还保留着那些老古董般的思想
They have an antiquated idea of how I should live my life.
尤其是我妈妈
Especially my mother.
我理解 我一直很敬爱她
I understand. I've always loved your mom.
- 真的吗  - 真的
- Really?  - Oh, yeah.
我父亲去世后她和我相处得很好
She was great with me when my dad died.
嗯
Mmm.
在你们眼中有着同样的忧郁
You both have the same kind of sadness in your eyes.
- 什么  - 你和你妈妈
- What?  - You and your mother.
听起来可真够别扭的 爱德华
That is a weird thing to say, Edward.
哦 抱歉 我无意要冒犯你
Oh, I'm sorry. I don't mean to offend you.
我只是 在我看来她一直很忧郁
I just... she just always seemed sad to me.
当我还是小孩的时候
She has sad eyes.
我就认为她有一双忧郁的眼睛
And I've thought that since I was a little boy.
你们有同样的眼睛
You have the same eyes.
很漂亮的眼睛
They're beautiful.
能不能别说我跟我妈妈很像 我并不想像她一样
Just don't say I'm like my mom, okay? I don't wanna be like her.
有意思 可是我一直很羡慕你们家
It's funny, 'cause I always envied your family.
我感觉我在学校里就像戴了面具一样
I felt like such an impostor at school.
你也是 我一直以为我唯一一个有那种感觉的人
You did? I thought I was the only one who felt like that.
- 你  - 是啊
- You?  - Yeah.
我总是专注于变得完美但是
I was so busy trying to be perfect and...
- 但是你内心却与之相悖  - 是的
- And you don't feel that way?  - No.
就是这个让你变得如此完美
That's exactly what makes you so perfect.
你能成为一个伟大的小说家
You are gonna be a great novelist,
因为你在脑海中创造了一个
'cause you have created a
虚构的人物
fictitious character in your head about...
- 不是  - 是的
- No.  - Yes.
不是的
No.
我不这么认为
I don't believe that.
你为什么放弃了你的艺术家之路
Why'd you give up on becoming an artist?
因为我太愤世嫉俗了 所以成不了艺术家
Because I'm too cynical to be an artist.
我总觉得这样还是挺好的
I think that to be really, really good,
因为你得由内而外的展现
you have to come from
你内心的某处东西 而我可能没有
someplace inside that I'm just not sure I have.
你太低估你自己了
You underestimate yourself.
你难道没意识到吗
Do you know that?
爱德华 呃
Edward, um,
你愿意跟我回家吗
will you come home with me?
这可真是有点快了
Well, that's a bit forward.
是啊
Yeah.
我没想到德州的上流社会女子的首次亮相会是这样
It's not what I'd expect from a Texas debutante.
你知道的 她们都是荡妇 所以
Well, you know all debutantes are sluts, so...
嗯
Hmm.
嗯 嗯
Hmm. Hmm.
而且你也是我第一个迷恋的对象
And you were my first crush too.
我知道
I know.
我们收到了来自奥佐纳的报告
We got a report from ozona.
昨晚在高速公路上也有别人和你一样遇到了骚扰
Someone else harassed on the highway last night just like you.
如果你不介意 我们需要用你的指纹
If you don't mind, we could use your fingerprints.
我的
Mine?
车后备箱上有一大堆的指纹
There's just a bunch of prints on the trunk of the car.
用你的指纹能帮我们从中区分开来
It could help us sort 'em out.
还有别的事
There's something else.
什么事
Yeah?
我们找到了死因
We have the cause of death.
你的妻子头骨碎裂
Your wife had a fractured skull.
她可能是被锤子或是棒球棍所攻击
She was probably struck with a hammer or a baseball bat,
可能是一下或者两下 所以
probably just once or twice, so...
你女儿遭受了更多的罪
Your daughter had a much more difficult time.
她是窒息而死的
She was suffocated.
她的一条胳膊也断了
She also had a broken arm.
她们都遭受了强奸
And they had both been raped.
关于那间屋子你也说对了
It turns out you were right about that trailer, too.
怎么呢
How?
那伙人 就想你想的那样
Those fellas, they took your folks in there,
他们把你们关在里面
just like you thought.
你是怎么知道的
How do you know that?
我们在床柱上发现了你妻子的指纹
We found your wife's fingerprints on the bedpost.
- 那是谁的屋子  - 查明了
- Whose trailer is it?  - It's clear.
房主不住在那里 他现在在埃尔帕索
Guy doesn't even live here. He's in El Paso.
房屋被擅自闯入 有人一直住在那里
Trailer's been broken into. Somebody's been living in it.
那里面到处都是指纹
There's prints all over the place.
我们会对照房主的指纹一一检查
We're gonna have to check 'em against the owner's,
看看能不能把那些指纹分离出来
see if we can separate 'em out.
- 说得对  - 我还是抱有希望的
- Right.  - I'm hopeful, though.
房主去年秋天就不在那里了 所以
The owner hasn't been there since last fall, so...
看起来有戏
Looks promising.
有
Prom...
有戏
Promising?
你之前怎么没告诉过我
Why didn't you tell me this before?
你这可是要离开纽约
You're actually gonna leave New York,
搬到奥斯汀然后去那个该死的德州大学
move to Austin and go to the goddamn university of Texas?
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
我是说 你打算干什么
I mean, where is this gonna go?
你什么意思 我打算干什么
What do you mean, where is this going to go?
我要嫁给爱德华 这就是我打算的
I'm going to marry Edward. That's where this is going to go.
这话从你嘴里说出来可真是可笑
This is a ridiculous conversation.
现在结婚对你来说还太早
You're too young to get married.
真的吗
Really?
妈妈 去年夏天你还试着
Mom, last summer you tried
说服我得去嫁给贝斯
to convince me that I had to marry bass.
那个不一样
That is different.
贝斯和你门当户对
Bass is your equal.
哦 我的天呐 你竟然能这么说
Oh, my god. Did you just say that? You really just said that.
没想到能从你口中听到这句话 这可真是
That came out of your mouth. That's...
你为什么总是把我想的那么坏
Why do you always think the worst of me?
我并不是这个意思
That is not what I meant.
我的意思是 你的个性很强
What I meant is that you are very strong-willed,
而爱德华 尽管很温柔 但是对你来说他太弱了
and Edward, as sweet as he is, he's too weak for you.
我从不会用弱这个字来形容爱德华
Weak is not a word that I would use to describe Edward.
我会用敏感来形容他
Sensitive is a word that I would use,
咱们家里每一个人
which isn't a word I would
都配不上这个词
use to describe anyone else in this family,
可能除了库帕
except maybe Cooper.
别提库帕
Don't bring Cooper into this.
抱歉
Sorry.
你别这样 苏珊
Come on, Susan.
我知道咱们俩的关注点不一样
I know you think that we don't care about the same things,
但是你错了
but you're wrong.
出不了几年
In a few years, all these bourgeois things,
你现在不屑一顾的小资情调
as you so like to call them,
会对你来说非常重要
are gonna be very important to you,
而爱德华却无法给你这些东西
and Edward's not gonna be able to give them to you.
他没有钱
He has no money.
他不努力 他没有上进心
He's not driven. He's not ambitious.
我能向你保证 如果你嫁给了爱德华
And I can promise you, if you marry Edward,
你父亲也不会给你钱的
your father's not gonna give them to you either.
是 你说的对 他是不努力
No, you're right. He's not driven
其实他只是不如你所愿的那样去努力
the way that you would like him to be.
但是他很强
But he is strong.
你要比我的很多方面都要强
He's stronger than I am in a lot of ways.
只是 他只是有一种不同的力量而已
Just... he just has a different kind of strength is all.
一种不同的力量
"A different kind of strength."
那到底是怎样一种力量
And what kind of strength is that?
他有相信自己的力量
He has the strength to believe in himself
同时也相信我
and believe in me.
苏珊
Susan,
如果你一定要跟他约会的话
keep seeing him if you have to,
和他住在一起 我不管了
live with him, I don't care,
但是别嫁给他
but do not marry him.
我明白在你眼中的爱德华是什么样的 我懂你
I understand what you see in Edward. I get it.
不 我真的明白
No. No, wait, I do.
- 不 你不了解 你不明白  - 我了解
- No, you don't. No, you don't.  - Yes, I do.
他富有浪漫主义
He is a romantic.
但他同时也很脆弱
But he is also very fragile.
我在他父亲去世的时候看出来的
I saw that when his father died.
你别
Don't...
你别嫁给他
Don't do this.
你会后悔的
You'll regret it.
而且到最后你只会伤害爱德华
And you'll only hurt Edward in the end.
当初令你对他产生爱意的种种
The things you love about him now are the things you'll hate
出不了几年就会令你厌烦
in a few years.
你可能意识不到
You may not realize it,
但是你和我之间相像的地方比你意识到的还要多
but you and I are a lot more alike than you think.
不 你错了 我和你一点也不像
No. You're wrong. You and I are nothing alike.
是吗
Really?
走着瞧吧
Just wait.
我们最终都会成为自己母亲的样子
We all eventually turn into our mothers.
[亲爱的爱德华
[大作拜读，非常震撼，我深为感动]
[不知周二晚上你是否仍有空，很多话想说]
[爱你的苏珊]
- 喂  - 托尼·哈斯廷斯
- Yeah?  - Tony Hastings?
- 是我  - 哪位
- Yes.  - Who is this?
罗伯托·安德斯 我给你发了封邮件 收到了吗
Roberto andes. I've sent you an email. You get it?
是的
Yes.
你认识这个人吗
Well, you recognize the guy?
- 不认识  - 该死
- No.  - Shit.
真该死 你确定吗
God damn it. You sure?
是的 整个事情现在都很模糊
Yeah. The whole thing's just a blur.
嗯 你的车子上全部都是他的指纹
Well, his prints are all over your car.
也在屋子里发现了他的指纹 他的名字是史蒂夫·亚当斯
They found 'em at the trailer too. His name's Steve Adams.
他在加州有过犯罪记录 偷车
He's got a record in California. A stolen car,
被告强奸却又宣判无罪 我已经发出了通缉令
acquittal on a rape charge. I put out an apb on him.
托尼 他是我们找到的唯一线索
He's the only lead we got, Tony,
而且我很确定不再有其他的证人
and I sure as hell don't have any other witnesses.
你确定你认不出他
You sure you don't recognize him?
不
No.
妈的 你怎么回事
Fuck. What's wrong with you, man?
你想不想把那些人都抓起来
Don't you wanna put these guys away?
想 我当然想
Yeah, of course I do.
这整件事就是有些
The whole thing is just some...
记忆模糊了
Just a blank.
我确定是他
I know it was him.
可能吧 但最近没有人在附近看到过他
Well, that may be, but nobody's seen him around here lately.
听着 我跟你说实话
Listen, I gotta be honest with you.
目前情况不太乐观
Right now it's not looking good.
有时候 这些案子一连几个月或是几年都可能没有进展
Sometimes these cases go months or even years without a break.
你得做好心理准备
You need to prepare yourself for that.
你为什么这么努力地去写作
Why are you so driven to write?
我想这是种让记忆保持鲜活的方式
I guess it's a way of keeping things alive.
你知道的 让那些终将逝去的记忆 永久封存在文字里
You know, saving things that will eventually die.
如果我把它写下来
And if I write it down, then,
它就不会消失了
it'll last forever.
[西德克萨斯]
- 下午好  - 嘿 你好
- Afternoon.  - Hey, there.
抱歉我迟到了 在洲际公路上堵了会儿
Sorry I'm late. There was traffic on the interstate.
没关系
That's all right.
你看起来不一样了
You look different.
没胡子了
No beard.
你看起来 你看起来也不一样了
You look... You look different too.
是吗 我告诉你我们发现了什么
Yeah. So I'll tell you what we got.
我们昨晚发现了一起
We had an attempted hold-up
在商场超市快闭店的时候发生的持枪抢劫
at the supermarket in the mall last night just before closing.
我们抓住了其中一个劫匪
We caught one of the guys,
一个被击毙 还有一个逃跑了
one got killed and one got away.
你想让我做什么
What do you, what do you want me to do?
看看你认不认识我们抓的那个人
See if you recognize the guy we caught.
尽管我觉得没必要
You can look at the dead one too,
那个被击毙的劫匪你也可以看看
although I don't really think it's necessary.
我们知道他是谁
We know who he is.
是谁
Who?
史蒂夫·亚当斯
Steve Adams.
我去年给你发的邮件里那个你称之为特克的
The one you called turk that I emailed you about last year?
进来
Come on in.
你害不害怕面对面见这个人 敢让他见你吗
Are you afraid to look this fella in the eye? Let him see you?
不害怕
No.
挺好 我觉得这样会让他张嘴
That's good. I think it will help him talk.
是他 左边那个人
That's him, that guy on the left.
最左边的那个 是他
On the far left. That's him.
不 不 不 别走 小子
No, no, no, no, no, no. Hold up, son.
你没那么幸运 过来
You ain't that lucky. Get over here.
- 是这个人吗  - 是的
- This fella?  - Yes.
我明白了 好吧 我不认为他明白了
I see. Right. I don't think he understands.
卢 嘿 说你呢
Lou. Lou. Hey, you.
你是叫卢吧 你知道我的名字 我告诉过你
Your name Lou? You know my name. I told you.
- 是吗  - 是的 怎么了
- Yeah?  - Yeah. What's going on?
我想让你
Well, I guess I want you to
告诉我你之前见没见过这个人
tell me if you've ever seen this man before.
仔细想想 你之前见过他吗
Think carefully. You ever seen him?
不 我不认识他
No, I don't know him.
- 嗯  - 他是谁
- Hmm?  - Who is he?
何不你来告诉他 托尼 给他提个醒
Why don't you tell him, Tony? Tell him who he is.
去年夏天 这个人 卢 还有他的同伙
Last summer, this man, Lou, and his friends,
他们迫使我们洲际公路上开下马路
they forced us off the road on the interstate
其中两个强行进入我的车里
and two of them forced their
里面还有我的妻子和我女儿
way into my car with my wife and my daughter.
- 然后这个人…这个人  - 这个叫卢的人
- And then this man... This man?  - This man Lou?
是的 罗 他让我开他的车
Yes. Lou, he made me drive his car,
他带我到沙漠中间然后把我扔下
he took me to the middle of the desert and he left me there.
再后来就在那附近的地方
And later my wife and daughter were found dead
找到了我妻子和女儿的尸体
near the same place.
这么做可不对
Well, that ain't right.
你对于那个人的妻子和女儿有没有什么可说的
What you got to say about this man's wife and daughter?
我对此一无所知
I don't know nothing about that.
我活到今天就没见过他
I've never seen him before in my life.
那你给我说说雷和特克
What you gonna tell me about ray and turk?
- 谁  - 谁
- Who?  - Who?
你是个猫头鹰吗 卢 你是猫头鹰吗
What, are you an owl? You an owl, Lou?
- 我从没听说过他们  - 你从来没听说过他们
- I never heard of 'em.  - You never heard of 'em?
没有 长官
No, sir.
好吧
All right.
警官
Officer.
把他关起来
Put him up.
- 你确定他就是那个人吗  - 是的 绝对确定
- Are you sure this is the man?  - Absolutely, yes.
你能在法院上 在伪证罪的惩罚下宣誓吗
You'll swear in a court of law under penalty of perjury?
我能
Yes.
好的
Good.
好 我们找到卢了
Well, we got Lou.
我会以谋杀罪起诉他
I'm gonna charge him with murder.
什么 你有足够的证据了吗
What, do you have enough evidence?
哦 当然了 我们有你
Oh, you bet, between you
还有他留在车里和屋子里的指纹
and the prints in the car and the trailer.
什么 他在扔下我之后回到那间屋子里去了吗
What, he went back to the trailer after he left me?
是的 看起来是这样 呃 他
Yeah, looks like it. Uh, he
可能只是回去告诉他们你在哪
probably just went back to tell 'em where you were.
这就是为什么他们带着尸体回来的
That's why they came back with the bodies.
他们是 他们是打算把你杀了
They were, they were gonna kill you.
你明白了吗
You see? Yeah.
我敢打赌那个雷就是持枪抢劫里的第三个同伙
I bet your friend Ray's the third fella in the hold-up.
- 那现在怎么办  - 你就等着开庭吧
- What now?  - Well, you're gonna wait for trial.
我得去找雷
And I'm gonna go find ray.
别忘了你下午三点在博物馆有董事会
Don't forget you have a board meeting at the museum at 3:00.
抱歉 你刚说什么
I'm sorry. What was that?
你又失眠了是吗
You didn't sleep again, did you?
你知道我的 我从来不睡
You know me. I never sleep.
我的前任丈夫曾称我为夜行动物
My ex-husband used to call me a nocturnal animal.
什么前任丈夫
What ex-husband?
我不知道你有前任丈夫 什么时候的事
I didn't know you had an ex-husband. Since when?
几年前读研究生的时候
A couple of years in graduate school.
很奇怪 我最近总是想起他
It's weird, I've been thinking about him a lot lately,
然后他最近寄给我一本他写的书
and then recently he sent me this book that he's written
这本书
and it's
很暴力也有点悲伤
violent and it's sad,
他把这本书命名为夜间动物并在题献词署上了我的名字
and he titled it nocturnal animals and he dedicated it to me.
你爱过他吗
Did you love him?
是的 我爱过他
Yeah, I loved him.
他那时候是个作家 我当时对他没有信心
He was a writer and, uh, I didn't have faith in him.
我有点慌乱还对他做了一些很糟糕的事情
I panicked and I did something horrible to him.
一些无法原谅的事 真的
Something unforgivable, really.
- 你先离开的吗  - 我离开他的
- You left him?  - I left him.
我很粗暴地离开了他
I left him in a brutal way,
选择了英俊又时髦的哈顿
for the handsome and dashing hutton.
- 他的确是英俊又…时髦  - 是的
- Who is very handsome and dashing. ...And dashing.  - Yes.
你有过这样的感觉吗 就是你的生活要发生一些
Do you ever feel like your life has turned into something
你从未打算过的改变
you never intended?
没有
No.
当然没有 你才刚开始你的人生
Of course not. You just started living your life.
你真的是一点都没睡是不是
You really didn't get any sleep, did you?
没睡
No.
[复仇]
这幅画是从哪来的
Where did this painting come from?
你什么意思 这从哪来的
What do you mean, where did it come from?
你给我们买的 不记得了吗
You bought it for us, remember?
这是大约八年前的一个系列的一部分
It was part of the series like eight years ago.
- 挺棒的 不是吗  - 是的
- It's great, isn't it?  - Yeah.
那是什么
What is that?
哦 我的天哪 这个太酷了
Oh, my god, it's so cool.
这个软件能让我看到在婴儿床里的薇洛
It's this app that lets me watch Willow while she's in her crib.
真的吗 你不信任你的保姆吗
Really? Do you not trust your nanny?
不 不 我信任她 我只是讨厌她 所以
No, no, I do. I just hate her, so...
我只是想在薇洛的一天时间里
And I would like to be more involved
和她多接触 所以
with Willow throughout the day, so...
你看 那是她
Look. There she is.
音效真是难以置信 你能真切地听到她呼吸
And the sound's incredible. You can actually hear her breathing.
如果我想的话 我还能和她说话
And I can talk to her if I want to.
对不起 我很抱歉 我
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. I'm...
- 你没事吧  - 没事
- Are you okay?  - Yeah.
嗯 我只是
Yeah, I just...
我想我看到了一个人
I thought I saw someone.
没错 你是看到了一个人
Well, you did see someone.
是小床里的薇洛
That's Willow and she's in her crib.
她睡着了
She's sleeping.
很抱歉把你电话摔坏了 我可以
I'm really sorry about your phone. I can, um...
没关系 反正下周又发布新款了 所以
It's fine. A new one comes out next week anyway, so...
谢谢
Thanks.
走吧
Shall we?
她们在等我们
They're all waiting for us.
我们没有合同义务 好事儿
We're under no contractual obligations. Which is good.
我知道对于这件事大家的意见有分歧
I know we all have different, you know, opinions about this,
但是我认为
but as far as I'm concerned...
无论如何 我想我们应该让她走
Anyways, I think we should cut her loose.
她已经不是当初我们看中的那个人了
She isn't who she sold herself to be when we hired her.
我不同意 我认为目前要留着她
I disagree. I think we should keep her for now.
- 为什么  - 因为她很棒 我们都喜欢她
- Why is that?  - Because she's great and we all like her.
她要的只是大家的支持和多一点时间 仅此而已
She just needs our support and a little bit of time, that's all.
- 这样未必有效  - 我们得炒了她
- But it's not working.  - We need to fire her.
哈默博物馆有位上佳人选 我们可以撬过来
There's an awesome candidate that we could steal from the hammer
当然要快
if we move fast.
我同意琳达的意见 我们既然招她进来 应该支持她
I agree with Linda. We hired her. We should support her.
换了医生
New doctor?
没有 换了发型
No. New haircut.
但是苏珊 不是你上次开会提出
But, Susan, you were the one who brought it up last meeting
要有变动吗
that you were looking for a change.
我记得 但是现在我认为我们要留下她
I know, but now I think we should keep her.
有时候
Sometimes it's...
有时候变动太大
Sometimes maybe it's not such a good idea
可能并不好
to change things quite so much.
我不明白 我们干嘛来这
I don't get it. What are we doing here?
该死
Shit.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
嗯没事 跟我来
Yeah. I'm fine. Follow me.
这就是雷·马科斯
That's ray Marcus.
大家都知道他经常跟
He's been named as a frequent companion
卢·贝茨和史蒂夫·亚当斯混在一起
of Lou bates and Steve Adams.
他干点零活 电工和水管工
Part-time electrician, part-time plumber,
所以能搞出那么个出彩的马桶
hence the clever toilet facilities.
他很符合你和
He's not a bad match to your description
另一个劫匪的描述
and the fella at the hold-up.
没留下指纹 这点我们以前就领教过
No fingerprints, but we knew that before.
不明白为什么会没有他的指纹
I wonder why there aren't any fingerprints.
这个 很可能他当时把手放在你妻子身上
Well, his hands were probably on your wife.
除了一桩已撤销的强奸指控 他没有案底
His record's clean, except for a rape charge that got dropped.
牧营酒吧的酒保告诉我
I heard from this barman at this place, line camp bar,
雷和一个叫莱拉的女孩住在这里
that ray lives here with a girl named Leila
但他另外有个据点
but he also keeps another spot
瞒着她把别的女孩带到那里
to take girls she don't know about,
因你这案子而曝光的那间屋子 之前很可能就是他的据点
probably your murder trailer before it got notorious.
他看起来像不像那家伙
Does he look like he could be the guy?
就是他
Yes, that's him.
好
Good.
我们找他聊聊
Let's talk to him.
- 喂 雷  - 见你妈的鬼
- Hey, ray.  - What the fuck?
你他妈的谁啊
Who the hell are you?
从我这儿滚出去
Get off my property, man.
见鬼 我晚点打给你
Shit, I'll call you back.
我有事问你
I wanna ask you some questions.
滚
Fuck you.
老子正忙
I'm occupied at the moment.
- 什么事  - 问几个问题 仅此而已
- What's that?  - Just a few questions, that's all.
- 你跟我们走一趟  - 什么事 我啥都没做
- We need you to come with us.  - What for? I ain't done nothin'.
- 我没说过你做了  - 那就在这儿问
- I ain't saying you did.  - Well, ask me here.
不行 我们得开车带你走一段
No, we need you to take a little drive with us.
行了 快点完事 跟我们走
Come on, finish up what you're doing and let's go.
你不能转过身去吗
Do you mind turning round?
相信我 我也很不想看 但是
Believe me, I wish I could, but...
见鬼了
Fucking unbelievable.
好了 够了 快点
All right, that's enough. Come on.
快点
Come on, now.
行了 快点 穿上 快点
All right, come on. Get dressed. Come on.
- 你讯问我  - 对啊
- You questioning me?  - Yeah.
对 我们正在进行这事
Yeah, that's what we're doing,
- 不是吗  - 你还没宣读我的权利
- ain't it?  - You ain't read me my rights.
- 雷 你了解你的权利  - 你应给宣读给我听
- You know your rights, ray.  - You're supposed to read 'em to me.
我已经读过了你的权利 对吧托尼
I read you your rights, didn't I, Tony?
嗯
Uh-huh.
我已经读过了
I read you your rights.
你这可是非法的 伙计
This ain't legal, man.
我应该有律师什么的吧
I'm supposed to have a lawyer or something.
冷静点 帅哥
Calm down, sunshine.
只是非正式的讯问 没别的
This is just informal questioning, that's all.
你得合作 我并没有指控你任何事
You're helping me out. I ain't charged you with nothing yet.
不过 如果你想要律师 我可以把你带到警局
Now, if you want a lawyer, I can take you down to the station
给你加一项指控
and charge you with something.
噢 别这样 伙计 听着 别带我去警局
Oh, come on, man, listen, you ain't gotta take me in.
我已经在回答问题 不是吗 来吧
I'm answering the questions, ain't I? Come on.
你问吧 我来回答
Give me some questions. I'll answer your questions.
见到你之前 我对于抢劫案的了解
I don't know any more about
并不比今天在这儿知道的少
this hold-up than I did before I met you.
这么说吧
I tell you what,
我要问你一个别的问题
I'm gonna ask you a different question.
- 你记得这辆车吗  - 哪辆车
- You recognize this car?  - What car?
这辆 我们正在坐的这辆车
This one. The one we're driving around in.
为什么我应该认得这辆鬼车
Why should I recognize this fucking car?
你不觉得它很熟悉吗
It ain't familiar to you?
它不会让你想起什么吗
It don't remind you of nothing, take you back?
- 为什么它会  - 你不记得开过这车
- Why should it?  - You don't remember driving it?
- 我想我记得  - 是吧 司机呢
- I think I'd know.  - Yeah. How about the driver?
什么 这家伙
What? This fella?
正在开车的伙计 我的朋友托尼
This fella sitting behind the steering wheel. My friend Tony?
你还记得他吗
You remember him?
我看不见他的脸 让他转过来
I can't see him. Make him turn around.
托尼 停车
Stop the car, Tony.
转过来 看看这个垃圾
Turn around and look at this piece of shit.
- 他是谁  - 你不记得他了
- Who is this guy?  - You don't remember him?
- 不记得  - 托尼 你记得他吗
- Can't say I do.  - You remember him, Tony?
- 记得  - 好 让他也想起来
- Yes.  - Well, refresh his memory.
去年夏天在洲际公路
Last summer on the interstate.
告诉他 你记得他做过的那些事
Tell him what you remember he did.
你杀了我妻子和女儿
You killed my wife and my daughter.
疯了 我从没杀过人
That's crazy. I never killed nobody.
- 跟他说他全部经过  - 嗯
- Tell him the whole thing.  - Mmm-mmm.
你和你的狐朋狗友在洲际公路上
You and your buddies on the interstate,
把我们挤到路边
you forced us off the road.
- 跟他说那些朋友的名字  - 卢和特克
- Tell him who his buddies are.  - Lou and turk.
雷 你现在想起来了
You remember that, ray?
你还记得和你那些狐朋狗友在洲际公路上转悠
You remember horsing around on the interstate with your buddies,
和别的车辆玩贴近斗胆游戏
playing chicken with the other cars?
你们疯了 真疯了
You're crazy. That's crazy.
你强迫我们停下来
You made us stop and we
我们爆胎了 卢和特克换了胎
had a flat tire and Lou and turk fixed it.
然后你和特克开我的车 带走了我妻子和女儿
Then you and turk got in my car with my wife and my daughter
- 你强迫我和卢开你的车  - 然后呢 托尼
- and you forced me in your car with Lou.  - What then, Tony?
卢把我带到灌木丛 把我赶下车
Lou took me out into the brush and kicked me out.
之后你们又开我的车回来
And you came back in my car
你大声叫我 想引诱我进你们的圈套
and you called out for me, trying to lure me into your trap.
你们来到卢丢下我的地方
You came back where Lou had left me
噢 雷 那就是你们折返的原因吗
oh, is that why you went back there, ray?
- 你们真他妈疯了  - 托尼 告诉他我们在那里找到了什么
- You're fucking crazy!  - Tell him what we found there, Tony.
- 你来说  - 非得我来说吗 雷 你不知道吗
- You tell him. Do I have to?  - Don't you know, ray?
你们疯了 真疯了
Y'all are crazy. It's crazy.
你们把我妻子和女儿的尸体
The bodies of my wife and child
带到那里丢弃
which you took back there and dumped.
你就是凶手 我记得你
You're the one. I know you.
雷 你有什么要说的
What do you say, ray?
你们疯了 你们犯了大错
You're crazy. You're making a big mistake.
嗯 我可不这么想
Mmm. I don't think so.
雷 我可不这么想 把双手放到前面
I don't think so, ray. Put your hands out in front of you.
- 你没权这么做  - 没权吗
- You got no right.  - Got no right?
权利 权利 你和你的狗屁权利
Rights, rights, rights. You and your goddamn rights.
说到你的权利 我想告诉你
Speaking of rights, I just wanna let you know
我已经录下了我们全部的谈话
I'm recording this entire conversation.
瞧 你清楚吗
There. You clear?
- 哼  - 好啦 我们走 托尼
- Mmm-hmm.  - All right, let's go, Tony.
现在我们去一个地方 你大概会记得
Now, we're going to a place you might remember,
你可以告诉我们那里发生的事情 从而帮你自己脱困
and you can help yourself out by telling me about it.
不过如果你不记得
But if you don't remember,
托尼也记得 好吧
Tony does, all right?
喂 伙计 我很难过你失去了亲人
Hey, I'm sorry you lost your folks, man.
真不幸 但这事跟我没有任何关系
It's a shame. But I didn't have nothin' to do with it.
- 这是哪里  - 你知道这个地方
- What's this place?  - You know this place.
- 对天发誓 我不知道  - 托尼 你也下车
- Honest to god, I don't.  - You wanna get out, Tony?
- 雷 我们进去看看吧  - 看什么呢
- Shall we have a look inside, ray?  - What for?
过来 我们进去看看
Come on, let's take a look.
好了 好了
All right, all right.
噢 我想你是在床上强奸了她们
Oh, you raped them on the bed, I suppose.
- 我从没强奸过任何人  - 别兜圈子了 雷
- I never raped nobody.  - Stop fucking around, ray.
我们查过你的案底 我们知道卢博克市那个姑娘的事情
We seen your record. We know about that girl in lubbock.
那个指控已经撤销了 我从没强奸过别人
The charges were dropped. I never raped nobody.
雷 我要知道
I wanna know, ray.
我要知道你对她们所犯罪行的全部经过
I wanna know the exact story, what you did to them.
- 这你得问别人  - 我要知道她们说过什么
- You'll have to ask somebody else.  - I wanna know what they said.
我要知道我妻子说过什么
I wanna know what my wife said
我要知道我女儿说过什么
and I wanna know what my daughter said.
我要知道你是如何杀死了她们
I wanna know how you killed them.
我要知道她们是否知道所遭受的一切
And I wanna know if they knew it was happening to them.
我要知道她们的感受
I wanna know what they felt!
我要知道她们是否感到痛苦
I wanna know if they hurt.
回答我
Answer me!
说啊 狗杂种
Answer me, you fucking bastard!
这样是不是好一点
Is it better?
你可能会误会我的意思 但是
You're gonna take this the wrong way, but, um,
我觉得你应该
I think that you should
写其他事情 而不是写你自己
write about something other than yourself.
人都是只写自己 不写其他东西
Nobody writes about anything but themselves.
我只是 我一边看一边在走神
I just, my mind started to wander when I was reading it,
这算是写得不好 对吧
and that's not good, right?
我不知道怎么办 也许 你知道
I don't know what to do. Maybe, you know,
也许我没有写书的潜质
maybe I don't have a book in me.
也许你该给自己一点空间 做点别的
Maybe give yourself some space. Just do something else.
- 你能不能别这样  - 怎么了
- Can you not do that?  - What?
因为这样 这样让我觉得你对我没信心
Because it... That makes me feel like you don't believe in me.
- 爱德华 我可没这么说  - 是 你没这么说
- Edward, that's not what I said.  - No, you didn't say that.
但是你脸上的表情在这么说
But you're saying it with your face
你的叹息也在这么说
and you're saying it when you sigh.
不管怎样 当你要我重回学校的时候
Whatever, you're saying it
你说的是这个意思
when you say you want me to go back to school.
是的 我是想要你重回学校
Well, yeah, I do want you to go back to school.
我没觉得这有什么不对
I don't see what's wrong with that.
我想说 我只是个现实主义者
I mean, I'm just being a realist.
我想说 你打算就开一间书店 写一本小说
I mean, you're gonna work at a book store and just write a novel,
似乎这就是你想要的生活
like that's what you wanna do with your life?
我想说 这样很浪漫 但是怎么办 只是这些吗
I mean, that's really romantic, but, like, what? This is it?
- 就是这些 这就是…  - 你这么说话就像你妈妈
- This is it? This is what...  - You sound like your mother.
你总是说我让你觉得我多像她
Well, you always said that I reminded you so much of her, so...
你知道 这就是我不想看你的作品的根本原因
You know, this is exactly why I don't wanna read your work
因为你总是心怀戒备
because you always get so fucking defensive.
是 我当然要心怀戒备
Yeah, of course I'm defensive!
你知不知道这是什么滋味
Do you know what it feels
当你醉心创作的时候
like to put yourself out on the line creatively
你所爱的人却告诉你
and then have someone you
他们看不懂
love tell you that they don't understand it?
我不知道什么滋味 因为我没有创造力
No, I don't, because I'm not creative...
那是因为你选择了不去创作
That's because you choose not to be.
我不想吵架 我又累又烦
I don't wanna fight. I'm tired and I'm edgy.
整晚都在写作
I've been writing all night.
我只希望你能喜欢它 好吗
I just wanted you to like it, all right?
谢谢你
Thanks.
有个消息会令你不快
I got some news you're not gonna like.
他们要释放雷·马科斯
They're letting ray Marcus go.
什么 什么意思他们要释放他
What? What do you mean, they're letting him go?
地区检察官说我们没有铁证
The d.A. Says we don't have enough hard evidence,
我们只有一些不重要的证据
what we have is circumstantial.
他要的是铁证
He needs corroboration.
托尼 我真的很抱歉
I'm real sorry, Tony.
太遗憾了
It's a goddamn shame.
至少你狠狠地打了他一顿
At least you got to lay a good belt on him.
这哪里够 我们还能做什么
No, that's not enough. What else can we do?
我可以想点什么
I can think of something.
但你要快点过来
You'd better get here quick, though.
他不会在这儿呆很久
He ain't gonna stick around for long.
好 我这就出发
Okay, all right, I'm leaving now.
什么
What?
我跟你说过 我得了肺癌 已经扩散了
I told you, I got lung cancer. It's metastasized.
- 但你一直在抽烟  - 是啊 该抽还得抽
- But you smoke all the time.  - Yeah, well, that's how it works.
现在戒烟有什么意义 我还能活一年
What's the point in quitting now? I'll be dead in a year.
有个叫简克思的家伙
It's this fella named jenks.
是法庭指派给雷的律师
He's the lawyer the court appointed for ray.
他来自达拉斯 有点小聪明
He's a little smartass from Dallas.
他和地区检察官达成协议让雷得以释放 这就是政治
He and the d.A. Made a deal and ray got off. Politics.
你什么时候跟我说过你病了
When did you tell me you were sick?
你看 他们想要赶走我
See, they're trying to force me out.
他们已经找了一个人来接替我的工作
They already got another fella lined up for the job.
我不明白你在说什么
I don't understand what you're talking about.
他们就这么撂下一单谋杀案
They'd drop a murder case to do that?
是啊 只要他们能弄到理由和材料
Oh, yeah. Give 'em the reason, ammunition.
他们说我这单案子准备不足
They said my case wasn't well-prepared,
是草率粗心完工的
was a sloppy job, slapdash,
没有证据 证据获取不当
no evidence and evidence improperly gathered,
在法庭上根本站不住脚
won't stand up in court.
检察官是个胆小鬼
The d.A.'S too much of a
不敢接可能会输的案子
chickenshit to take a case he might lose.
卢的案子他们会起诉
They're not dropping Lou.
但是 如果放走了雷 就他妈太糟了
Well, it's no fucking good if we don't get ray.
好
Good.
这正是我希望你会说的
That's what I was hoping you'd say.
他们想要我退休
They want me to retire and
到别处去享受我的肺癌福利
enjoy the benefits of my cancer somewhere else.
- 见鬼去  - 你从没跟我说你得了癌症
- Fuck that.  - You never told me about the cancer.
雷的问题是他有不在场证明
The problem with ray is his alibi.
你有家人吗
You have a family?
- 雷申辩说他当时跟那个小  - 波比
- Ray claims he was with that little... Bobby.  - Bobby.
怎么
What?
你有家人一起生活吗
Do you have anyone in your life?
没有 没老婆 也没
No. No wife or...
我有个女儿在科普斯
I have a daughter in corpus.
她帮过你吗
Has she been a help?
她都不知道 她又能做什么
She doesn't know. What can she do about it?
不管怎样 雷申辩说
Anyway, ray claims
她当时和那个叫莱拉什么的小姑娘在一起
he was with that little girl, Leila whatever her name is,
她为他作证
and she backs him up.
她姨妈则为她作证
Her aunt backs her up.
我们怎么办
What are we gonna do?
这取决于你有多想伸张正义
It's a question of how serious you are about seeing justice done.
你懂我的意思吗
You get me?
我吃不下 想吐
I can't eat. Gonna throw up.
你如果不吃东西 又怎么去做好事情
How are you gonna get anything done if you can't eat?
有时能吃点 有时吃不下 这里糟透了
Sometimes I can, sometimes I can't. This place is terrible.
我需要你吃点东西
I need you to eat something.
现在让我问你一个私人问题
So let me ask you a personal question.
不会记录在案 只有你知我知
Off the record, between you and me.
你想要我怎么对付雷·马科斯
What do you want me to do with ray Marcus?
那么你能怎么对付他
Well, what can you do with him?
任何你想要的
Anything you goddamn like.
但是我记得你说过
But I thought you said that...
听我说
Listen,
我不会有任何损失
I got nothin' to lose.
我不能让这个混蛋检察官搞砸我的最后一桩案子
I'm not gonna let this asshole d.A. Fuck up my last case.
我也不能袖手旁观地看着杀人犯逍遥法外
I'm also not gonna stand by and watch a murderer go free.
这些年我已经见过太多雷·马科斯
I've seen too many sick
这样的变态狂都逃脱了惩罚
fucks like ray Marcus get off over the years.
现在 你愿意走法律以外的途径吗
Now, are you willing to go outside of strict procedure on this?
好
Yes.
- 你确定  - 是的
- You sure?  - Yes.
我是安德斯
Andes here.
你在说笑 好了 谢谢
You're kidding? All right, thanks.
雷刚刚出现在牧营酒吧
Ray just showed up at line camp.
我打算让那个小笨蛋喝高
I'm gonna let that little idiot get nice and liquored up
然后再把他抓起来 带到我的地盘
and then I'm gonna go grab his ass and take him to my camp.
我想你跟我一起去
And I want you to come with me.
我们打算扣留他一阵子 玩一玩他
We're gonna keep him for a little while, work him over a bit,
给他来点难堪 让他受点罪
get a little rough, make him suffer.
然后我们再看他怎么做
And then we'll see what he does.
你觉得怎么样
Would you like that?
你要明白这样是行不通的
You have to realize that this is not working.
我们合不来 我们相差太多
We are not working. We are too different.
- 我们不合适  - 苏珊 别说了
- We are not right for each other.  - Susan, stop.
我们不合适吗
We're not right for each other?
就是不合适
No, we're not right for each other.
我们非常相配的啊
We are perfect for each other.
不 一点都不相配 爱德华
No, we're not perfect for each other, Edward.
如果我们没有生活在现实世界里
We may be perfect for each other
那可能的确很相配
if we didn't live in the real world,
但问题是我要活在现实里
but I live in the real world
我需要过得更稳定有序一些
and I need a life that is more structured.
- 我需要更稳定有序的未来  - 喂
- I need a future that is more structured.  - Hey.
我也想变成你要的那种伴侣 但我做不到
I want to be the person that you want me to be, but I just can't.
- 你不需要改变啊 你已经很好了  - 我做不到
- You are. You are.  - I can't be that.
冷静点 别这么说
Hey, no, stop.
我真的很想成为你所以为的那个我
I, I really wanted to be this person that you thought I was,
我很努力了 但我真的不是那样
I really did, but I'm just not that person.
- 我 我很愤世嫉俗 又世俗实际  - 不 听我说
- I'm, I'm cynical, I'm pragmatic.  - No, look...
- 不 我就是这样 我特别实际  - 你只是害怕 你只是怕了
- No, I am. I'm a realist.  - You're afraid. You're afraid.
不 我没有害怕
No, I'm not afraid.
- 我们都共同经历过那么多大风大浪了  - 我不是怕
- We've been through this so many times before.  - I'm not scared.
- 我不是怕 我只是不高兴  - 好吧
- I'm not scared. I'm unhappy.  - All right.
我非常非常不高兴
I'm just really, really unhappy.
你真的非常
You're so...
你真的是个非常好的人 而且你是如此
You really are so wonderful and you're just so
敏感又浪漫 而且
sensitive and romantic and...
- 很懦弱 没错  - 什么 我没说你懦弱啊
- Weak. That's right, yeah.  - What? I did not say you were weak.
- 你以前说过好多次  - 我可没说你懦弱
- You've said it so many times before.  - I did not call you weak.
你明明说过的 再说一次也无妨啊
You've said it before, so why don't you say it again?
- 不就是懦弱嘛  - 我没说过你懦弱
- Weak.  - I did not say you were weak.
- 我肯定没说你懦弱  - 你爱我吗
- I did not say you were weak.  - Do you love me?
- 这不是重点  - 不 这就是重点
- That's not the point.  - No, that is the point.
- 不 才不是重点  - 就是重点
- No, it is not the point.  - That is the point!
- 这根本不重要  - 你还没回答我
- That is not the point.  - You didn't answer me.
- 没错 我爱你  - 好啊 你要是爱一个人的话
- Yes, I love you.  - Well, when you love someone,
你会想办法解决问题
you work it out.
而不是一味地断舍离
You don't just throw it away.
你要珍惜爱情
You have to be careful with it.
因为可能再也没有第二次了
You might never get it again.
我不能跟你继续下去了 爱德华
I can't do this with you anymore, Edward.
我没法坚持下去了
I just can't keep doing this.
苏珊
Susan...
你不能一直
You can't just walk away from things
只知道逃避啊
all the time.
- 行了 行了  - 哦 该死 得了吧
- Come on. Come on.  - Oh, shit. Come on.
我都说过了 我啥也不知道啊
I told you, I don't know nothin' about this situation.
你干嘛不去问问别人呢 老哥
Why don't you go ask in there, man?
我一会再来找你 听到没
I'll see you in a minute, okay?
好不好啊 宝贝
Okay, sweetie?
我们准备去我的地盘
We're going to my camp.
在白溪那边 就在他们抓走你家人的屋子附近
It's in white creek near the trailer where they took your folks.
你跟着一起来吧
You follow.
坐起来
Sit up.
我的天 我要吐了 托尼 过来 快点
Oh, Jesus. I'm gonna be sick. Tony, get over here, quick.
给你 用这个 行不
Here, you use this, right?
要是他有什么不规矩的地方就打他
You shoot him if he gets out of line.
呕
Boo.
喂 哥们 你们这样做不合法吧 要是合法的话
Hey, man, this ain't legal. If this were legal,
你们就直接带我去警局了 才不会来这种鬼地方呢
you'd have taken me to the station, not this fucking place.
现在我们说了算 小子
It's all the legal we need, boy.
- 你们也没有什么新证据  - 是吗
- There ain't no new evidence.  - Oh, yeah?
要是你们有证据了 干嘛不直接把我抓进去呢 嗯
Why don't you take me in if you got new evidence? Huh?
因为我更喜欢这里 气氛比较融洽
I like it better here. It's more relaxed.
你这套把戏我可是见识过的
It seems to me you tried this trick already.
要是你以为这个人能对付得了我
If you think this guy's gonna break me down,
- 那你已经知道这办法行不通了  - 是啊没错
- you already seen that don't work.  - Oh, yeah,
但是要是我告诉你
but what would you say if I told you
你朋友卢·贝茨已经把你
your friend Lou Bates implicated you
在哈斯廷斯一家谋杀案中的罪行供出来了呢
in the Hastings murders?
要是卢真把我供出来了 你们早就把我抓进去了
If Lou had done that, you would have taken me in.
哦 别担心 我们会送你去警局的
Well, don't worry, we'll get you to the station.
- 不用担心  - 哦 谁啊
- Don't worry.  - Oh, who's this?
- 啊 看看谁来了  - 你个混蛋
- Well, looky here.  - You son of a bitch.
好了
All right.
好了 快点 小子 过来
Okay, come on, boy. Get over there.
- 卢 你他妈跟这人说什么了  - 我啥也没说啊
- Lou, what'd you fucking tell this guy?  - I didn't tell him nothin'.
不可能 他说你告诉他
No, he said you told him I
我是杀了这人老婆孩子的凶手
was the one who killed this guy's wife and kid.
啥 这不是他跟我说的吗
What? That's what he told me about you.
你可是执法人员 这啥情况啊
You're supposed to be the lawman. What kind of bullshit is this?
闭嘴
Fuck off
俩人都闭嘴
both of you.
现在 你们俩有什么遗言想说吗
Now, do you two have any last words you wanna say to each other?
我觉得吧 托尼
I think what we should do, Tony,
我们现在就应该干脆杀了他们
is we should just kill them right now.
放他们逍遥法外可挺烦人的
It's gonna be rough for 'em out there,
不知道会有什么影响
not knowing how it's gonna come.
或许雷的死因是拒不受捕 嗯
Maybe Ray'll get killed for resisting arrest, huh?
深夜晚归
Coming home late at night,
可能被窃贼开枪打死
he might get shot by a burglar.
哦 你觉得不好受吗 小子
Oh, you feeling uncomfortable, boy?
喔 起来
Ooh. Come on up here.
真的 你好像真的觉得不好受啊
Yeah, you look like you're feeling uncomfortable.
- 什么  - 抱歉 我很抱歉
- What?  - Sorry. I'm sorry.
你说什么
What's that?
我不会杀你的 小子
I ain't gonna kill you, son.
我可是警察
I'm a policeman.
怎么 你要哭啦
What, you gonna cry?
真要哭啦
Are you gonna cry?
哦哟 好吧 既然你都这么难受了
Aw, okay. Well, since you're feeling so uncomfortable...
托尼 过来
Tony, get over here.
拿好
Take this.
- 来吧 站这 好不  - 求你别
- Go on, right here, okay?  - Please don't.
站好 站好
Fuck. Right here, right here.
站好 好吗
Right here, okay?
- 好了  - 喂 喂
- Right.  - Hey, hey.
那我呢 我也觉得难受了
What about me? I might be feeling uncomfortable too.
哦 是吗
Oh, yeah?
好吧 起来吧
Okay, come on up.
好了 重归自由
There you go. Free as a bird.
好啦 怎么样
Okay? How about it?
你怎么想 托尼 这俩人要怎么处理
What do you say, Tony? Now, what shall we do with these two?
你要怎么做
What you gonna do?
你要怎么做 伙计
What you gonna do, son?
拜托
Come on.
快跑
Let's go...
他有枪的
He's got a gun.
- 波比  - 开枪 托尼 开枪
- Bobby?  - Shoot 'em, Tony. Shoot 'em.
回来 你们两个混蛋
Come back here, you little fuckers!
不 不
No. No.
不要 求你
No, please.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我的余生都要在悔恨中度过了
I'm gonna live to regret this.
我现在好后悔
I regret it now.
你知道的 我信天主教 我不支持人工流产的
You know, I'm catholic. I don't even believe in abortions.
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
我真没用
I feel so useless.
你可千万别这么说 你总能想到最好的做法
You're anything but useless. You always know exactly what to do.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我觉得自己再也无法直面爱德华了
I just don't think I'm ever gonna be able to look at Edward again
毕竟我对他的孩子犯下了这种罪孽
after what I did to his child.
他永远不会知道的
He'll never find out.
我都做了什么 我都做了什么
What did I do? What did I do?
我保证不会有事的
I promise it'll be okay.
我会让一切都好起来的
I'll make it okay.
哦 天啊 不
Oh, my god, no.
爱德华
Edward.
托尼
Tony.
嗯
Mmm.
喂
Hey.
你知道我除了开枪别无选择 对吧
You know I had to shoot him, right?
我他妈一点都不在乎你开枪打他
I don't give a goddamn fuck that you shot him!
你开枪打他我很高兴
I'm glad that you shot him!
他终于死了我他妈高兴死了
I'm fucking glad that he's dead!
我应该可以阻止的
I should have stopped it!
我应该保护好她们的
I should have protected them.
我应该想到会那样的
I should have seen it coming.
我本来可以阻止的
I should have stopped it.
好了 好了
Hey, now. Hey, now.
我本来可以阻止的
I should have stopped it.
嘘
Shh.
- 好了  - 我本来可以阻止的
- It's okay.  - I should have stopped it.
好了
It's okay.
喂
Hey.
冷静点
You're okay.
我应该阻止的 波比
I should have stopped it, Bobby.
看着我
Look at me.
你是个好人
You're a good man.
好了 起来吧
Come on. We gotta get up.
雷跑上公路了 他肯定要去搭车
Ray gets to the road, he's gonna hitchhike.
我们要在他搭上车之前抓住他
We gotta catch him before he gets a ride.
听我说
Now, listen to me.
走到一个三岔路的时候 你走左边那条路
When you get to the fork in the road, you veer to the left.
然后你就会回到他抓走你家人的地方
That's gonna take you back towards where he took your folks.
我怀疑他会往高速路走
I suspect he's gonna go for the highway.
我去那个方向追
I'll go that direction.
你带着这个 我车里还有一把
You take this. I got another one in the car.
- 波比  - 怎么
- Bobby...  - What?
你做这些会惹上麻烦吗
Are you in trouble for all this?
我也不知道 但我一点都不在乎
Hell, I don't know. I don't really give a shit.
我快死了 你忘了吗
I'm dying, remember?
妈的
Fuck.
是你啊 你的伙伴呢
You. Where's your pal?
他马上就到
He's on his way.
警察们呢
Your cop friends?
他们就在附近
They're around.
他们在这
They here?
现在就我自己
It's just me for the moment.
哦
Oh.
就你和这把你根本不会用的枪啊
You and that fucking gun you don't know how to use.
卢怎么了
What happened to Lou?
他死了
He's dead.
啥
What?
龟儿子
Fucking son of a bitch.
你那个朋友可会有大麻烦的 你知道吧
That's big trouble for your friend, you know that, right?
我不觉得
I don't think so.
你不觉得
You don't think so?
好吧 那你到底想干嘛
Well, then, what the fuck do you want?
你拿把破枪想干嘛
You and that silly gun.
你好像拿着还挺顺手的呢
I've seen how handy you are with that thing.
坐下 坐下
Sit down. Sit down.
快坐下不然我一枪崩了你
You sit down or I'll fucking kill you.
听着 哥们
Listen, man...
为什么像你这样的好人
Why does a nice guy like you
会跟安德斯这种杀人不眨眼的人一起玩呢
hang out with a guy like Andes who kills people?
你才杀人不眨眼
You kill people.
她们遭遇不幸
They had it coming to 'em,
你的老婆孩子 但是你
your fucking wife and that kid, but you...
你误会我了 那是个意外
You got me wrong, it was an accident.
你说是意外
It was an accident?
我是很爱惜名声的
I got a certain pride in how people talk to me.
我也有底线的
There are certain things I don't put up with.
要是有人说我犯了什么事
When someone accuses me of something,
那绝对是侮辱
that's a fucking insult.
锅可不能白背
It gives me the right.
要是我的女人说我跟别人鬼混
If my woman accuses me of fucking somebody else,
那我就会去找个女人鬼混
well, then, I'll go fuck somebody else.
要是你闺女觉得我是强奸犯 那我就强奸她
If your daughter thinks I'm a rapist, then she gets raped.
你对我们犯下那种罪行 绝不可能逍遥法外 绝不可能
Nobody gets away with what you did to us. Nobody.
绝不可能
Nobody.
真的
They don't?
不可能
Nobody.
好啊 那你直接杀了我呗
Well, then, you should just kill me, then.
对吧
Right?
你应该杀了我
You should fucking kill me.
老哥 你啥也不懂
Man, you know nothing.
杀人很好玩的
It's fun to kill people.
大家都应该尝试一下
You of all people should try it sometime.
好玩
Fun?
杀人好玩
It's fun to kill people?
你杀我妻子女儿的时候
Did you have fun
觉得好玩嘛
killing my wife and daughter?
起来
Get up.
起来 去啊 快
Get up. Go on, now.
去啊 去啊
Go on. Go on.
去啊
Go on.
我记得你老婆
I remember your fucking wife.
我记得我睡过你老婆
I remember fucking your wife.
你太懦弱了
You're too weak.
太他妈懦弱 知道吗
Too fucking weak, you know.
你太懦弱所以什么也做不了
You're too weak to do anything about it.
去你妈的
Son of a bitch!
爱德华
Edward.
[来自爱德华·谢菲尔德的新邮件]
[亲爱的苏珊]
[请告知周二晚上何时何地见面]
[爱德华]
这边 先生
Right this way, sir.
汤姆·福特作品
夜行动物